eajournals.org 2019-05-25

# Privacy Policy - EA Journals

**Introduction**

As an international business the EA Journals takes the privacy and protection of data and information very seriously, and are dedicated to treating the personal information of all those we deal with such as our customers, colleagues, suppliers etc., in a way that meet the legal requirements of the countries in which we operate. As part of dealing with the firm’s products and services, visiting our websites and contacting the business, information and data are collected. Our privacy policy is written to safeguard and maintain the privacy of personal information. It describes what data is collected, the way it is used, the rights customers and other individuals have over that data and legal basis for its use.

**About EA Journals**

The EA Journals serves individuals, professional and academic communities by producing and providing access to contents that help them and their businesses work better and to make decisions quicker. The EA Journals focuses on providing high quality academic research with practical implications for business practice and publishes specialised books. We aim to, providing academics and practitioners with a platform to share ideas and realise their individual potential. This Privacy Policy describes how the EA Journals collects, uses and protects your personal information to provide you access to our content, publishing and knowledge services in EA-journals.

**What we collect**

This section highlights the personal information that may be collected when using our products and services, and other personal data that may be received from other sources.

  * Educational, nationality and professional background information

  * Contact details, such as your full name, email address, telephone numbers postal address
  * Payment information, such as a credit or debit card number
  * Comments, feedback, posts and other content submitted; and
  * Interests and communication preferences including marketing permissions where appropriate.

**Your personal information are collected and use in the following main categories:**

  * As customer / consumer data, related to transactions
  * As contact data, which includes academic and corporate customer contact data such as subscriber / user data
  * Product / intelligence data, collected through customer and market research surveys
  * Author, Editor, Learned  Society and Training Organisation and Lecturer data associated with the delivery of publishing contracts and services;

**How personal information is used and Why**

**This section spelt out in detail how and why we use personal information.**

  1. **Personal information is used for lawful Processing in Europe:** The EA Journals collects and uses personal information in Europe on lawful bases as required by the European data protection laws include; where you have consented to its use, where our colleagues believe it is in your vital interests to share your personal details, for example with emergency services, where it is necessary for entering into or performing a contract with you, where we have a legitimate interest to do so, provided your rights do not override these interests, and finally where required to comply with our legal obligations
  2. **Marketing:** We will use your personal information to send you newsletters, offers or other marketing emails that keep you up to date with our news, events and products that may be of interest. You may have given us your consent for this, by opting in, or we may be entitled to rely on your implied consent or our legitimate interests which is dependent on your interaction with us as well as the laws of the country where you live. A provision is made where you can opt out of future marketing emails and the information on how to do so when you’re personal information is collected and on every marketing email sent.

**Publishing:** When you publish with us, your personal information will be used disseminate and promotion your research, as a commercial firm. Your name and affiliation will be published as part of authored work. Personal information is also used for payments or other purposes, because it is vital for contractual agreements and performance with our organisation. Also **,** it is important to note that   videos and photos may be taken with respect to your published research works which may be used for promotion.

**Product enquiries, sales and administration:** When a customer is making an enquiry it is important to note that we collect information such as your name, country, job title, company information or academic affiliation, postal address, e-mail address and telephone number. This information is used to respond to the enquiry before you enter into a contract. Where you have registered for or purchased a product or services, your personal information will be used to provide that product or service, communicate about it and handle payments, as is necessary for the performance of the contract entered into with us. Payment information which are also collected ranges bank details and credit/debit card number/bank details and billing addresses. You data will also be collected where payment card processors are used to facilitate payment card transactions on our website. This will be used in line with the data processors’ privacy policy.

**Customer Management:** Your personal information may also be used to perform internal analysis of the usage of our products and services. The reason for this is to improve our products and services, advance new products and forecast for customer’s attitude and behaviour in the near future as part of our interest as a commercial organisation.

**Mobile Apps and Websites Analytics** : It is likely that we may combine visitor session information, or other information collected through tracking applications, with personally identifiable information that will help us comprehend, evaluate and measure your online experience and determine what products, promotions and services that will be of interest to you.

**Compliance with our legal obligations** : The compliance with international trade sanction laws and regulations are very necessary and we do that with our customers by screening them. Where a customer has an issue during the screening exercise, the customer will be communicated and we will stop dealing with such customer.

**How personal information are protected**

Any personal information given to us will be treated with utmost confidentiality and security **.** A number of physical and technical measures is used to keep data safe and prevent unauthorised access to, or use or disclosure of personal information.

**International transfer of personal information**

As a global entity, personal information may be retrieved by our colleagues and third-party service providers from locations outside of the European Economic Area, whose data protection laws may not be as extensive as those in Europe. Appropriate protection takes place to ensure your personal data remains adequately protected and is treated in line with this Policy.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a small text file containing a user ID that is automatically placed on a user’s computer or other device when visiting a website. Although it does not contain personal information however, it may use in tracking the activities of customers on the Website and collecting information on demographic to improve the Website; and offering time-saving or personalized features on the Website.

**Who we share personal information with**

As a global entity, we may share your person information with the following types of third party, to help us in providing products and services to you:

  * Web hosting providers
  * Article submission, copy-editing and peer-review providers
  * Secondary content aggregators
  * Library discovery services
  * Government and institutional scholarly research repositories
  * Content platform providers
  * Email marketing providers

  * Indexing and abstracting providers

It is important to note that we only share your personal information with such third parties to an extent necessary for them to provide such assistance.

**Sharing with other Organisations** : In accordance with local data laws and where applicable your consent, we may share your personal information with trusted partner organizations for the purpose of their marketing. If your personal information is subject to European data protection laws, we will not share it with third parties for their marketing purposes, unless you have actively given us your consent to do this. Your personal information may also be shared with third parties in a situation where the company wants to sale, merger, acquisition, partnership, joint venture. It also important to note that sometimes we may be  required  by law to disclose your personal information were a  court, the police, another judicial or law enforcement body, or government entity has asked us to do so.

**How long will your personal information be retained**

Our clients’ personal information will only be retained for as long as is necessary and as permitted by applicable laws.  Your personal information will only be retained for as long as is necessary and as permitted by applicable. It will be deleted or securely destroyed.

**Updating your information and marketing preferences**

Your personal information is vital and we want to ensure that you are in control of them at all times. We will always give you the chance to opt out of future marketing communications. Details on how to do that will be specified when we collect and specified your marketing information   on every marketing email we send. However, you can make changes where necessary, update your personal information or even opt-out of future marketing

**Your rights**

It is important you know your right and exercise them.  Your rights under the General Data Protection Regulation include;

  * The right to confirmation whether or not we have your personal data and, if we do, to obtain a copy of the personal information we hold. This is known as subject access request;
  * The right to have inaccurate data rectified;
  * The right to have your data erased. This does not however apply where it is necessary for us to continue to use the data for a lawful reason;
  * The right to request the restriction or suppression of their personal data, such as, we will stop using the data but we may continue storing it)
  * The right to obtain your personal data that you have provided to us, on the basis of consent or performance of a contract, and where technically feasible, transmitted in a common electronic format to you or directly to another company.
  * The right to object to the use of your data. Specifically, you have the right to object to our use for marketing and in relation to automated decision making, including profiling where there may be legal or similarly significant effects.

If you would like further information on your rights, wish to exercise them or any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us via [info@eajournals.org](mailto:info@eajournals.org)

**Changes to Privacy Policy**

Changes to the privacy policy can change at any time and for us to keep up with the changing legislations, we may revise this Privacy Policy at any time and without notice by posting a revised version on this website. Regular visitation to the privacy policy section of our website implies that you are aware of any changes. This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with the website’s Terms and is also subject to these Terms.

This Privacy Policy was last updated in May 2018
